KALEN WALLIN

+1 (308) 882-8850 | kalenwallin1@gmail.com

kalenwallin.com | linkedin.com/in/kalenwallin/ | github.com/kalenwallin

Focused Computer Science grad with a specialty in full-stack development and a stellar academic record. Carries diverse programming skills including Python, JavaScript, Django, and CSS, and experience with Agile methodologies. Proven success in improving developer performance, notably reducing CircleCI testing times by 50%. Experienced with international web programming and game engineering at Reykjavik University. Combines academic leadership with real-world software development expertise.

EDUCATION

 $\textbf{University of Nebraska-Lincoln} \mid Lincoln, \, NE \mid Aug \, 2019 - Aug \, 2023 \mid GPA: \, 3.96/4.00$

Graduated with Honors and Highest Distinction in Computer Science with a minor in Mathematics. Developed Minieval with a team of six students in the Game Development club.

Reykjavik University | Reykjavik, Iceland | Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 | GPA: 4.0/4.0

Studied Web Programming and Game Engineering Architecture abroad.

Chase County High School | Imperial, NE | Aug 2015 - May 2019 | GPA: 4.0/4.0

Valedictorian of Class 2019

President of Future Business Leaders of America and national qualifier in Cyber Security State qualifier in Cross Country and Track and Field

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wallin Farms | Imperial, NE | Part-Time Python Programmer | Aug 2023 - Present

Developed an OCR-based Python program to convert images of corn tickets into structured Excel reports, significantly reducing manual data entry time for employees.

Mystic Rhoads Productions | Lincoln, NE | Part-Time Intern | Jun 2023 - Jun 2023

Created social media posts, updated the WordPress website, designed graphics, and researched NPO grants.

FarmAfield | Lincoln, NE | Full-Time Django Programmer | May 2021 - Aug 2022

Maintained the <u>farmafield.com</u> Django web app with an Agile team of 5 developers for 40hrs/week.

Notable features include Dark Mode, Email Preferences, <u>Rural Energy Partners Landing page</u>, and Notifications. Reduced CircleCI testing times by 50% by introducing Parallel testing.

University of Nebraska-Lincoln | Lincoln, NE | Teaching Assistant (CSCE 361) | Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Helped students understand Software Engineering through weekly office hours.

Graded their assignments in coordination with three other teaching assistants.

NOTABLE PROJECTS

baldorf | Lincoln, NE | Part-Time Unity Game Developer | Aug 2022 - May 2023

Updated a Unity mobile game for a nonprofit organization using Agile methodologies with a team of 6 students. Discussed requirements and accomplishments with the CEO weekly.

Released Android, iOS, and WebGL builds to the sponsor monthly.

Received individual Rockstar award for placing in the top 15% of students and best team honorable mention.

Distinction and Honors Thesis | Lincoln, NE | Part-Time Researcher | Aug 2022 - May 2023

Designed a competitive multiplayer game mode for baldorf based on research of competitive mobile games. Wrote a 50-page paper on the subject and defended it in a 35-minute presentation.

Portfolio | Lincoln, NE | Part-Time Web Developer | Dec 2021 - Present

Designed and developed a portfolio website to show off experiences. Built with Blazor, then Astro.

Made a separate portfolio using Django based on Netflix's web app design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Python | JavaScript | Django | CSS | HTML | Git/GitHub | Microsoft Teams | VS Code

Intermediate: C# | Blazor | Unity | CircleCI | SQL

Familiarity: .NET Core | Amazon Web Services | C | C++ | Java | NodeJS | TypeScript